Joaquín Maúrtua

Full Stack Web Developer

Arequipa, Perú (GMT-5) (+51) 993 406 228 joacomaurtua@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/joaquinmaurtua/ https://joacomaurtuadev.com/

I am a Full Stack developer with more than 2 years of experience. My technology stack includes front-end technologies such as HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, ReactJs, NextJs, VueJS, as well as back-end tools such as NodeJs, Express and MongoDB. Throughout my career, I have worked with complex projects, such as building an ecommerce, implementing critical functions such as product customization, order management and payment processing. In addition, I have designed custom user interfaces and tailored applications to specific customer needs to ensure customer satisfaction. In addition to my core technology stack, I have experience with a variety of additional tools and methodologies, including Bash, Git, Github, Jira, Trello, ShortCut, and SCRUM. I also hold certifications in integration-checkout Mercado Pago and SCRUM. In my next position, I am looking for a challenging role that will allow me to use my experience and skills in developing solutions, especially ecommerce, to make a significant contribution. I would value a position where I can work in a collaborative and innovation-driven team on disruptive projects that create value in the market.

EXPERIENCE

(N1) Freelance

Full Stack Developer — November, 2020 - March, 2021

During my time as a Freelance Full-Stack Developer, I focused on providing customized and efficient technology solutions for local SMB businesses. My main responsibilities included:

- Contribute in the construction, maintenance and continuous improvement of applications developed in HTML5, SCSS/CSS and Javascript, with the objective of satisfying the needs and objectives of my clients.
- Design and develop responsive web applications consuming information from Rest Full APIs previously created to meet business needs.
- Thanks to the website I developed for a local restaurant, I was able to increase the prestige and digital presence of the restaurant.
- Performed the role of Social Media Manager and Community Manager for local SMBs, maximizing their revenue through the
 use of Facebook's ad manager.
- During this period, I managed to acquire a wide range of technical and soft skills, such as teamwork in collaboration with the client, effective communication, time management and the ability to adapt to work under pressure.

Technology Stack: HTML5, SCSS/CSS, MERN.

(N2) Front-end Innpactia Inc Developer — October, 2021 - January, 2023

- I participated in the successful migration of the company's platform (static page) to ReactJS (single page application), technology selected by the development team, as well as react bootsrap to handle styles and redux to handle application states. I learned to work under standards and design patterns to maintain an orderly and coherent code for the whole team.
- I made interactive and didactic presentations at daily meetings to report on the progress of assignments, which significantly improved team communication and collaboration.
- I carried out the production staging of the platform environment using the AWS-EC2 deployment tool, ensuring that response times were optimal and that scalability requirements were met.
- I collaborated on technical documentation to improve knowledge transfer among the team and ensure documentation is up to date and easily accessible.
- I used JIRA for task management, assignment and status review, which allowed me to accurately track progress and ensured that assignments were delivered on time and efficiently.

Technology Stack: MERN, React, AWS-EC2, JIRA, Node.js.

(N3) Full Stack Ecommerce Buke Store SAC Developer — September, 2022 - April, 2023

- Designed and improved the interfaces using a boostrap template as a base for both the Dashboard for the administrator and the store for the buyer user.
- I implemented key functions such as product customization, order management and payment processing.
- Implemented in collaboration with a partner, the data models, as well as the server configurations, the connection to the database, the implementation of the controller view model and the administration of the application endpoints.
- Worked in collaboration with a partner to create custom user interfaces in line with the client's needs.
- Implemented automated and manual testing to ensure software quality.
- I used JIRA for task management, assignment and status review.
- I used my analytical and problem-solving skills to tailor the application to the client's specific needs and ensure client satisfaction.
- Demonstrated my expertise in developing custom e-commerce applications and my ability to work in a team and meet deadlines.

SKILLS

Programming Languages: Advanced: Javascript; Intermediate: Python.

Frameworks Tools: Advanced: ReactJS, Redux-toolkit, NextJs, NodeJS, Express; Intermediate: VueJs, Vuex, ReactNative, Material-UI,

ReactStrap; Basic: ThreeJS, React Three Fiber 3D, WebOpenGL, GSAP.

Database: Advanced: MongoDB, Mongoose. **Tools:** Git, Jira, Slack, Short Cut, Trello.

Agile: SCRUM, KANBAN.

Languages: English B2, native Spanish.

EDUCATION

Universidad Católoica San Pablo - Arequipa, Peru. BA, Computer Science, December 2020. Coding Dojo - Santiago, Chile. Full Stack Developer, MERN - Stack, September 2021.

CERTIFICATIONS

Checkout-pro Mercado Pro Certification - Mercado Pago. 2022. Scrum Foundation Professional Certificate - CertiProf. 2022.